Mahmut Baran Turkmen

+44 7591 426 744 | MahmutBaranTurkmen@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/mahmut-baran-turkmen | github.com/cjxe London, United Kingdom

SUMMARY

I am a recent Computer Science graduate from Durham University. During my studies and freelancing work experiences, I gained expertise in building responsive UIs, REST APIs, trading bots, chatbots and websites. These experiences include working both independently and within a team. Currently, I am learning new tools and concepts by building full stack projects!

EDUCATION

Durham University 09/2019 – 06/2022

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

- Modules: Algorithms, Data Structures, Networks, Distributed Systems, Databases, UX Design and Cryptography
- Dissertation: Universally Accessible Order Book Style Decentralised Exchange(paper)
- Former Course Representative

EXPERIENCE

Blockchain Developer (Contractor)

03/2022 - 03/2023

Node.js, Express.js, Jest, Solidity, ether.js, IPFS, OpenAPI, Git, diagrams.net, Google Slides

Ajinomoto Turkiye

- Coded a REST API with 2 main endpoints by following an MVC architectural pattern using the Express.js framework
- Set a coding standard using ESLint and Prettier to maintain a scalable codebase
- Documented the built API endpoints using OpenAPI Specification for future testing and improvements
- Asynchronously worked with two teams (the front end team and the SAP microservice team)

Chatbot Developer(project) (Contractor)

07/2021 - 08/2021

Node.js, Cloud Firestore, ESLint, Prettier, Git

PulseAIO

- Boosted server activity by 15% by coding a chatbot in JavaScript that assigns points to users based on their activity
- Integrated the Cloud Firestore database to store user activities and track prizes based on the given architectural design
- Logged all functions with different logging levels to track and prioritise errors

PROJECTS

Transfer Coins(project) (Work in Progress)

01/2023 - present

React, AWS, Next.js, Storybook, Tailwind CSS, Husky, GitHub Actions, Vercel, Figma

- Designed a SaaS project using Figma(figma)
- Currently coding the components using React and Tailwind CSS while isolating them with Storybook(storybook)
- Enhanced the deployment success rate from 80% to 100% by integrating tests using Husky into Git hooks

Decentralised Exchange(project) (Bachelor's Project)

12/2021 - 05/2022

Solidity, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ether.js, OpenZeppelin, Hardhat, diagrams.net, Figma

- Designed, coded, and hosted a central limit order book style decentralised exchange where all data is saved on-chain
- Designed a single-page website using Figma and turned it into code with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- The app passed 100% of 7 buy and 7 sell order integration tests using Hardhat and Remix frameworks

Algorithmic Trading Bot(project)

08/2021 - 01/2022

Node.js, Bash, Dedicated Server

- Coded an algorithmic trader that profited £2,000 with £15,000 through applying a given strategy
- Achieved a 200% increase in the success rate of our strategy by renting a dedicated server to host our EVM full node

ADDITIONAL SKILLS & INTERESTS

Community Manager

02/2021 - 03/2022

• Saved 1 person-hour per day while scaling a group from 750 to 4,000 members by utilising and building chatbots for our Telegram, Twitch, and Discord groups

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, Python, Rust, Solidity, Bash, SQL, HTML, CSS, OpenAPI
- Frameworks: Next.js, Express.js, Bootstrap, Hardhat
- Technologies: React, Storybook, Node.js, MongoDB, Cloud Firestore, Redis, MySQL, SQLite, Figma
- DevOps: Git, Terraform, Docker, Husky, GitHub Actions, Jest, Selenium, ESLint, Prettier, DigitalOcean, Vercel
- Other: AWS, Agile, Scrum, Kanban board, TDD